SAM JOYCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DETAILS

PHONE

07800645405

EMAIL

samjoyce18@yahoo.com

LINKS

sam-joyce.com

github.com/sam-joyce

SKILLS

HTML5 & CSS

JavaScript

React

Java

Building performant API's with NodeJS and Spring Boot

NoSQL and MySQL Databases

Testing with Jest, Enzyme and JUnit5

Agile project delivery

PROFILE

Professional software developer with experience of client delivery in both the tech and finance space. I have held leadership roles in both my previous career, managing a client independently whilst working at PwC, as well as my current role at _nology, where I have managed and ran B2B courses with a variety of clients.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Development Coach, _nology.io

London

Jun 2020 — Present

After completing my 12 week bootcamp I was offered the role of Junior Software Development Coach at _nology.

I quickly progressed from working alongside a more senior coach to running my own courses such as the consumer course, as well as B2B engagements. My role now involves delivering courses and teaching modern software development practices and technologies

Data Management Associate and Tax Accountant, PwC

Birmingham

Sep 2017 — Dec 2019

I worked as a personal Tax Adviser full-time whilst studying for my ATT qualification, which I achieved with all first time passes. I had exposure to client management and deadline delivery as well as being awarded my first client that as a Trainee Associate I managed through my second "tax season".

EDUCATION

Software Development, _nology.io

London

Jan 2020 — Apr 2020

During these 12 weeks I created a number of personal projects, which varied in complexity. I designed and created my own game of Minesweeper and during weeks 6-10 of the course we completed a client project (The Drop). For this project I led the team for a week which involved holding daily scrums as well as an end-of-week retrospective. I worked on both backend and frontend aspects and also completed code reviews of other people's completed tickets.

A-Levels, Kind Edward VI

Lichfield

Sep 2014 — Jun 2016

Mathematics (C) - Economics (C) - Geography (C)